Before the Conjuring, there was Annabelle.
Annabelle is a horror film directed by John R. Leonetti.
A couple begins to experience terrifying supernatural occurrences involving a
vintage doll shortly after their home is invaded by satanic cultists.
Mia Form, played by Annabelle Wallis.
John Form, played by Ward Horton.
Father Perez, played by Tony Amendola.
Evelyn, played by Alfre Woodard.
Detective Clarkin, played by Eric Ladin.
Sharon Higgins, played by Kerry O'Malley.
Annabelle is a 2014 American supernatural horror film directed by John R.
Leonetti, written by Gary Dauberman, and produced by Peter Safran and James Wan.
Starring Annabelle Wallis, Ward Horton and Alfre Woodard, the film is a spin-off and prequel to the
2013 film The Conjuring, serving as the second installment in The Conjuring Universe.
It was inspired by a story about a doll named Annabelle popularized
by paranormal investigators Ed and Lorraine Warren.
Principal photography began in January 2014 in Los Angeles.
The film premiered at the TCL Chinese Theatre on September 29, 2014, and was released
theatrically in the United States on October 3, 2014, by Warner Bros.
Pictures and New Line Cinema.
Produced on a $6.5 million budget, Annabelle grossed over $257
million worldwide despite negative reviews from critics.
A prequel, Annabelle: Creation, was released on August 11, 2017.
The film explores themes of halloween, prequel, evil doll, killer doll, spirit.
The tone is dark.